MATTHEW DOONAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER STUDENT

CONTACTS



021 045 8830



matt.j.doonan@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin. com/in/matthewdoonan-b569a1278



https://github.com/mattd oonan

QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Engineering (Software)

University of Canterbury
Present

COMPETENCIES

- Software Development
- Application Testing
- · Requirements Gathering
- Project Management
- User Experience
- Stakeholder Engagement
- Graphical User Interface
- Agile Methodologies
- Technical Documentation

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A highly ambitious, creative individual who has developed a comprehensive knowledge of the software development lifecycle (SDLC) and acquired solid programming experience as part of a university degree. Worked on multiple projects, including developing a buddy system, building an application that shows nearby electric power stations, and creating a game. Manages both front-end and back-end tasks, from producing website layouts to creating APIs and testing functionality. Possesses a genuine passion for technology, with a determination to develop systems that will improve peoples' and businesses' lives.

ACADEMIC JOURNEY

TEAM ANALYTICAL BUDDY (TAB)

University of Canterbury / Third Year

- Currently creating a team analytical buddy system that enables users to plan events and record the team's performance.
- Review new stories (features) with acceptance criteria that the Product Owner wants to be implemented into the application.
- Use the Agile project management framework to manage how features are implemented.
- Carry out research on the best APIs to implement for the application and come up with user-friendly designs.
- To date, a user-friendly application that works on any device has been developed successfully.

REVOLT

University of Canterbury / Second Year

- Researched, designed, and developed an application, 'Revolt', which would show nearby electric power stations.
- Initiated the utilisation of Gitlab to manage the project effectively and ensure deliverables were met (schedule, quality, specifications).
- Managed the front- and back-end of the application, ensuring features were implemented accordingly.
- Implemented a testing strategy using Cucumber, JavaFX, and JUnit tests which were integrated into the Git pipeline.
- Proposed and secured buy-in from the team to embed soft deadlines to ensure the project was able to be completed on time.
- Successfully fulfilled all requirements and received an A grade for the project.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- · Analytical | Critical Thinking
- · Team Player
- Communication
- Attention to Detail
- Planning | Organisational
- Time Management
- Problem-Solving
- Emotional Intelligence
- · Resilience | Adaptability

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- SQL
- GitLab
- Python
- Java
- JavaScript | TypeScript
- React
- Spring Boot Framework
- C Programming
- Socket Programming

MICROCONTROLLER DEVELOPMENT

University of Canterbury / Second Year

 Designed a ping-pong game to play between two microcontrollers using an infrared sensor.

ENGINEERS WITHOUT BORDERS

University of Canterbury / First Year

- Worked as part of a team to develop a sustainable solution to the plastic waste accumulation on Cape York beaches in Australia.
- Assumed the role of a Team Leader, coordinating the team's activities and projects from planning to reporting phase.
- Designed a solution that converted plastic waste into building brinks which mitigated waste issues and created new economic opportunities.
- Completed a detailed report with our research, analysis, and solution, which was presented to the academic team and colleagues.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BARTENDER

16 Tun / 2022 - 2023

• Completed various tasks from customer service to preparing beverages undertaking stocktake and resolving complaints.

COLLECTION DRIVER

SaveMart Limited / 2021 - 2022

• Worked both independently and as part of a team to deliver an efficient, compliant, and safe collection operation.

CHECKOUT OPERATOR

Countdown / 2019 - 2021

 Delivered a positive customer experience by building a strong rapport with customers, completing sale transactions, and resolving enquiries.